here I am this is me in
FaceTime and I deliberately am making
this video as kind of a video blog a
vlog of the stuff I learned today about
streaming with just a Mac so this is
this is the Mac that I that I have the
only thing that's attached to the Mac
right now is my stream deck so I can
push the record button on and off and of
course I'm using the presentation thing
from Mac which is really great you get
those Reaction Time those reaction
things um you know you get all that good
stuff right you get the the tiny mode um
where's the tiny mode that's this one's
not working right now there we go and
and you get you know you get this small
mode I mean I think I think I've showed
everybody all these cool things that you
get uh with Mac this is all part of the
Mac thing but what I wanted to have
people have a sample of is what it
sounds like when you just use the mic
from the computer when you use the mic
in the computer and you use the arguably
crappy camera which is still good it's
still a pretty good camera if you've got
good light um I've noticed it's really
bad in low light and so for that I've
used the pocket 3 uh which is really
wonky when compared to OBS it's kind of
a weird thing um and then of course
we've got the other problems um which
are related
to uh well they're not really problems
but when you when you're dealing with
the other camera you can actually have I
actually have the action 4 which is got
a wider field of view so it makes it
gets more of my my body in the shot um
when you do small like this with
FaceTime it actually works kind of nice
because it's you don't have the hands in
the shot and everything but it does it
does work kind of nice because it it is
kind of zoomed in on your face so I I
just wanted to do a quick demo video of
this of this discovery um but more
importantly I wanted to tell you how I'm
doing this right now this stream is
coming over Verizon and right now I am
pushing a bit rate of 59 or 6,000
kilobits per second over Verizon and I
have a mimo
antenna let me show you I have well I
can't quite show you that but I have the
Verizon I have the night the NEC your
Nighthawk with the mimo antenna attached
which I'll do a separate video about the
mimo antenna is on the ceiling so it's
got really really great signal and it is
fantastic I mean it is pushing 6,000
kilobits per second um because I it's
directly powered the battery is out of
it I'll do a whole video about how to
get the absolute most out of your single
Verizon account and that's an important
thing because um the alternative is
starlink and so today I just received my
weight list they gave me $250 credit and
they said well it's probably going to
take us another month to get you a
starlink well I don't have that kind of
time so if if it comes time for us to
leave I'm going to go ahead and leave
without the starlink and we're just
going to stream from the Verizon uh from
just one modem but how did this work
this worked because I turned on the
tower I turned my tower back on in my
house that I've been using forever to
stream from and I'm now doing the same
exact thing that I was doing to stream
my bell box orange pie rig so let me let
me talk about that for a second this is
a really big deal
so you know right now if you want to do
IRL streaming with any degree of
reliability and high quality you need
are we in Minecraft mode already how are
we in Minecraft mode
we can't possibly be in Minecraft
mode I don't believe you I don't believe
you I'm going to go check oh my God we
it's worse than Minecraft
mode it's low resolution mode right as
soon as I said high resolution this is
great I'm glad I'm glad we have this I'm
glad we have this I'm glad this is on
the video this is not Minecraft
mode okay this is low bandwidth mode and
I really want you to see this I'm so
glad we got this on video the reason
that you're getting this right now is
because the signal
between um the system between OBS on my
Mac very creepy Rob I know it's like I
wonder if it'll clean itself up it
should normally clean itself up it
doesn't look like this one is but watch
what we can do watch what we can do my
friends we can actually pause the
recording I'm going to pause the
recording temporarily
this is what we're about to do cannot be
done unless you have it set up the way I
do okay so I'm going to put it to pause
give me a second
pause and then we're going to actually
restart OBS so be
patient right so we're going to stop
streaming and then we're going to start
streaming
again start streaming that might clean
up the video a little
bit let's see if it does
and okay so there it cleaned up the
video I'm really glad that we actually
got that got to see that on the
stream okay I wanted you I want you to
see what just happened so did you see
how the stream didn't
die
right the stream didn't die at all the
stream stayed on but there was a hiccup
on purpose on the Stream and it got
creepy but you could kind of still hear
me and I looked really weird and
everything but there was still a stream
happening and that is something I've
become sort of used to doing with the
Bell box when you have a bell box on
your on your back and you're walking
around you're regularly going to have
these moments where the reception is
going to be really bad and you're going
to get this you know overly pixelated
sort of thing that was not Minecraft
mode by the way a few people said that
that was Minecraft mode that was not
Minecraft mode oh here we go again I'm
noticing that we're getting it again so
the the reason we're getting that is
because we are in a low signal area
right
now right and so if I stop the stream
and restart it stop
start all right let me try it
again let's see if it gets
there connecting connecting
connecting I don't know I don't know
we're going to see how long it takes
okay here we go we come back again we're
probably going to have to do this a few
more times so this is not good but it's
also not really
bad and the reason it's not bad is
because the stream has kept going even
though the signal has gone to zero and
anybody anybody out there who has been
doing any amount of streaming knows what
happens if you don't have what we just
had I regularly I click stop streaming
and restart streaming in order to
restart the
stream and each time I did it um well
here we go again it's it's it's breaking
down it is it's breaking down I think
it's probably breaking down because of
the because it doesn't have good power I
think it's breaking down because it
doesn't have good power this is another
problem I've noticed with the Mac
the Mac does not stream well unless the
unless it's plugged in when it's plugged
in it the modem works better and I I
don't I can't fully explain why that is
but that is definitely the way it is so
I'm still recording I going through all
of these trials with you because I want
you to see all the different things that
can happen when you're streaming with
one modem no matter how good the modem
is so the modem that I'm using right now
is the Nighthawk M1
and um it is you know it's the best to
breed out there so um again we're
pixelated right
now and we need to reset the pixelation
now here's something I can even do I can
even exit
OBS now um I am I'm burnt I'm all
burnt right so I don't it's not it OBS
is really sad right now
OBS is having a really hard
time it is it is having OBS is having a
ridiculously hard
time it's just not OBS is just not
happy yeah it's like stuck under
connecting mode again and here we go I
went I I already I just sent an f and
here's my my this is great I wish you
can see it here look at look at what
it's doing on my stream that's what it's
doing on my stream but this is great I
want I want people to see this because
this this will eventually clear
up um it takes TW it takes a long time
for it to clear up and it's I'm curious
how how is the
audio how is the audio uh been affected
so you can still see the chat on the
screen and everything right and as far
as I'm can see seeing the recording is
actually this is actually really good
too the recording is totally fine see
this is what people don't see they don't
see the this is what the stream sees the
stream sees this crappy this crappy
thing right they see this absolutely
horrible
stream that has to be reset by
restarting
OBS but they're still able to hear
you and they can still understand so
they can still participate and if you
happen to be in the middle of recording
a video like I regularly am about
something that needs to go up on YouTube
like maybe I'm doing a beginner Boost
video the quality of the video that gets
recorded is not affected by the signal
strength of the live stream and the
first thing to go with the live stream
is the high quality image which the
unfortunately everybody can see that I
can't even show it to you on YouTube
without showing you what it's doing to
them right now there's two ways to reset
this and these are both OBS problems the
first one is to just re to just hit stop
and start and that'll restart that'll
restart the OBS on my Mac that is
sending a signal to another OBS that's
running on my machine in my house on 100
gigabit Ethernet or gigabit Ethernet so
that's same thing I would do with my
bell box right I don't have to pay any
money for that that is all the same
amount of money I would pay for my
family to have internet there's no extra
charge for that so even though the
people are suffering through this like
really pixelated weird stuff right now
they can still see something and the
stream is still there that's the main
thing I want you to take away from this
they can still see the
stream right they can still see the
stream and the recording is still
happening they can still understand they
can still hear and all it takes for me
to reset is to either turn the stream
off start and stop or to start and stop
OBS now do I start am I am I sounding
like a robot
yet the last thing to go is usually
robot voice so like if if you're live
streaming and eventually the the
eventually the SRT relay will get so
screwed up that you'll start to talk
like a robot and at that point you just
need to re restart you just need to
restart everything now the problem with
that in the past is that if you restart
everything when you restart everything
you lose everybody because they have to
hit restart but if you are using the SRT
Bella boox relay and that is the main
takeaway from this so I can't show you
mine but the answer is this listen very
carefully this is very important if you
want to add a Mac or or any anything you
want to be able to turn your laptop on
the road into a Bella box
essentially and you already have a Bella
box all you have to do is type in the
ingest SRT URL am I breaking up the
sound is breaking up okay I think this
sound is about to go thank you for being
patient all those who are watching um
but I I'm about to finish this video
okay so you type in the
SRT you type in the SRT URL for the
inest the inest URL from your bell box
cloud that you're paying $10 a month for
right you're already paying $10 a month
for that so that you can use orange pie
and you can use Bell box you can use the
exact same SRT relay URL inside you can
actually go into your stream settings
and in fact I think I might be able to
show you this let's try that so if you
go to your stream
settings and um actually I can't I can't
I can't show you because it's going to
show my URL but I'll I'll get you pretty
damn close so if you go to settings this
but this button right here so you see
this button right here where it says
stream if you click on stream then once
you click on that you'll be able to
click on um something it'll say uh it'll
it'll say um custom right it's the very
top item you don't you change it from
twitch normally it's set to Twitch right
you change it from twitch to custom and
in custom you type in the SRT inest URL
from your bella box and that will turn
basically your your computer your laptop
then turns into for all intens purposes
a Bella box it turns into a Bella box
and then the Bella box is going to do
everything the same so everything else
is the same as far as your OBS that's
running at home so your computer here
including the SpaceTime this you know
the FaceTime mic and the FaceTime camera
they become the same exact things as if
you were using a bell box and the thing
that's so great about that is that you
can then plug another camera into into
your OBS on your Mac and you can use
that just the same as if you plug that
same camera into your orange pie to use
Bell box that's the end of this video
the people that are watching me have
been very very patient I have this is
all about low bandwidth streaming and
these people have been very patient
because I haven't reset the stream yet
because you know it's gotten really bad
and I probably sound like a robot but
they've been very patient with me but
the point of it is no matter how bad it
gets your stream doesn't die when you do
an SRT relay you do not need to buy IRL
toolkit you do not need to buy no SCU
antis SCU you don't need any of that you
can use the same SRT relay that you're
using for your orange P Bella box and
just use that URL in your OBS running on
any laptop that's the takeaway I hope
this has been helpful it took me very
long long to figure that out and I great
big gratitude to all the friends and who
have helped me to figure that out and so
now no matter how bad my stream gets
it's still a stream they're still up and
I can reset it without losing everybody
and forcing them to refresh their web
browsers that nobody wants that all
right that's all for that video talk to
you later